hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the tosa automation
playlist so continuing with our topic on
the test automation obstacles let's look
at our next obstacle which is known as
the tough cookie now what is this so we
have got kind of four text boxes as you
can see here and then uh the first edit
box uh when you click on this it reveals
a random text and this random text
includes three large numbers okay so
here is the first number here is the
second one and uh here is the third one
right what we need to do is we need to
extract all these three numbers and then
we need to enter it one by one into each
of this t text boxes so this is what uh
we need to
do now keep in mind that this particular
uh text which is generated is random in
nature so U the numbers could be
anything right now in order to automate
this particular problem we need to be
able to extract text using regular
Expressions okay so we have to use uh
regular expression and uh there we need
to use something called a named group
using which we can buffer some parts of
this particular expression using a
random rejects okay so let's see U how
we can do this in tosa so coming back to
our tosa work space uh the first step as
always is to uh scan the particular
module so we'll go to our obstacles here
uh we are going to scan a new
application
and then we are going to scan this
particular page so basically we need all
the four text boxes so um we are going
to select all of these different
controls okay and then um also I'm going
to rename the
module okay and then I'm going to save
this and then I'm going to close this
okay so now uh going back to our test
cases and the obstacles folder let's
create a new test case
here and let's rename
this okay and then I'm going to drag the
module and add it
here okay so obviously the first step is
to reveal the particular text or
generate the random text so for that uh
we need to click here right so we will
do that so that uh it's going to reveal
or generate the text so let's rename
this particular test tip as generate
text okay and then uh we are going to
add the same module again to perform the
remaining steps okay so I'm going to add
it here and then um I'm going to say
buffer
results
okay um so the first step is to
basically buffer all the three numbers
right so you cannot do it uh step by
step like you buffer normal uh values
here uh as I said we need to extract the
text uh which is dynamic in nature using
some regular Expressions right so for
this uh we have to use a particular
regular expression which is little
complex in nature so I have written it
down so that I don't make any mistakes
it's quite long but I'm going to explain
you this Rex uh what I have written here
right so let's expand this a little bit
so that we can see this okay so as you
can see this is the Rex expression and
then inside this okay so this carot sign
means uh this is the starting of the
expression and dollar means it's the end
of the Rex right so inside this we have
got the dot star which will basically
cover any particular uh text right and
then after that uh we have something
called the named group okay so this
named group it consists of the buffer
okay so this uh angular brackets number
one this is the buffer okay so this is
where uh the first number will be stored
okay and the number you know uh the rexs
for that would be 0 to 9 so all the
digits between 0 to 9 it could be any
number right and then uh we are saying
that there is more text so we have put
the plus sign and then again uh dot Star
as you can see here so that uh again uh
it could consider any random text which
is generated okay okay and then uh for
the second number we have again got a
named group okay so this named group is
formed of two parts so the first part is
the buffer name and the second part is
the expression okay so the expression is
the dynamic part which needs to be
buffered so when this is buffered it
will be stored in this particular number
two or whatever buffer name you Pro
provide and the same we do for number
three okay so this is how this whole uh
regular expression has been written so
that it can buffer all the three
randomly generated numbers and then it
can store in this buffer names okay so
this is a specialized named group uh
expression which is present in tosa okay
and this is how you can use this to
basically extract Dynamic parts of a
string and then you can save these
values to different
buffers now once uh we buffer this then
this problem becomes easier now we just
need to enter uh the buffer values into
the respective text boxes okay so here
uh we will be using the expression
simple buffer and then I will be using
number
one
okay and then here uh we will use number
two and in the third one we will use
number
three okay so this is how you can
basically solve this automation problem
so once you write the random Rex
expression
and then you can just uh extract all the
dynamic parts of that particular text
and then you can store them in different
buffers okay so now let's go back to the
test case let's change the work state to
complete it and let's try and run this
particular test
case Okay so one important thing to note
is whenever you are using uh something
like a named group then the input action
mode type is not supported okay so you
can see here input is not supported for
Rex values right so what we need to do
is we need to change the action mode
here to verify so let's go ahead and try
this one more
time okay so as you can see uh now uh it
clicked on the first text box to reveal
the randomly generated uh text and then
from there it extracted all the three
large numbers and it stored it into the
buffers and then it used that buffers to
enter it into all the three different
text boxes and the automation problem
was resolved okay so this is how you can
use the Rex and the named group to uh
solve these complex U automation
problems where you have to use some
random regular expressions and you also
need to buffer different Dynamic values
from a randomly generated
text that's all for this particular
video if you have any questions then
please leave it in the comments if you
like this video then please subscribe to
our Channel thanks for watching and I
will see you in the next
video